<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Poke</title>
    <link>https://poke.digital/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Poke</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 13:35:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://poke.digital/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Agents</title>
      <link>https://poke.digital/features/agents/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 13:35:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://poke.digital/features/agents/</guid>
      <description>Agents are operators which create metrics from your websites at regular interval. In addition, they create metrics by zone where the agent is deployed.
A zone is a concept affiliated to the team or enterprise whom deploy agents. Generally, each agent is deployed on each zone used by the team or enterprise.
HTTP The HTTP agent scrapes your websites in order to extract the response status and time. This agent emulates the user&amp;rsquo;s traffic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alerting</title>
      <link>https://poke.digital/features/alerting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 13:35:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://poke.digital/features/alerting/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High performance</title>
      <link>https://poke.digital/features/high-performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 13:35:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://poke.digital/features/high-performance/</guid>
      <description>Why being highly efficient? Monitoring is first class citizen while running any kind of service or infrastructure. Workloads can grow fast and it&amp;rsquo;s important for the monitoring solution to support this growth without being rethought every month so we can concentrate on the customer value. An other good reason is the cost ratio between the service and the monitoring cost to ensure your service is fine.
How do we achieve performance There are mainly two parts in the Poke architecture : the scheduler and agents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scalable</title>
      <link>https://poke.digital/features/scalable/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 13:35:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://poke.digital/features/scalable/</guid>
      <description>Poke rely heavily on Warp10, a very scalable platform for Time Series, and tries to reuse the same components to avoid complexifying the operational stack. It also comes with additional components like the Poke Scheduler, Poke Us, Poke Me and Poke UI.
Apache Kafka Apache Kafka is a horizontally scalable and fault-tolerant distributed streaming platform. Kafka is used by poke to distribute checks to agents, enabling :
 Scaling agents through partitions Using multiple groups to enable checks from different zones  Kafka is also used as an ingestion buffer in Warp10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time series</title>
      <link>https://poke.digital/features/time-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 13:35:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://poke.digital/features/time-series/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>User interface</title>
      <link>https://poke.digital/features/user-interface/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 13:35:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://poke.digital/features/user-interface/</guid>
      <description>The user interface provides an easy way to visualize metrics provided by agents. It is created in order to fastly highlight websites malfunctions.
Just behind there is an example of what you could see using the poke monitoring system:
As we can see, there are three paths of the domain google.com answering using HTTPS protocol which are monitored by poke. Furthermore, there are the HTTP response status and latency displayed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started</title>
      <link>https://poke.digital/documentations/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://poke.digital/documentations/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>All Poke&amp;rsquo;s components are hosted on GitHub under the warp-poke organisation.
This organisation provides some agents in order to check protocols:
 HTTP: https://github.com/warp-poke/http-rust-agent DNS: https://github.com/warp-poke/dns-rust-agent SSL: https://github.com/warp-poke/ssl-go-agent  Furthermore, there is an API that manage checks and their scheduling:
 API: https://github.com/warp-poke/poke-api.  Start using docker-compose On the poke-compose repository, there is all you need to setup a docker-based poke infrastructure. This infrastructure used the standalone version of each distributed components.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Concepts</title>
      <link>https://poke.digital/documentations/concepts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://poke.digital/documentations/concepts/</guid>
      <description> Poke is an open-source, multi-region, efficient and scalable web monitoring platform based on Time Series.
Poke&amp;rsquo;s main features are :
 Web Performance Monitoring Website Defacement Detection Trend Analysis Advanced Alerting  Performance Monitoring Website Defacement Detection Trend Analysis Advanced Alerting </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Page</title>
      <link>https://poke.digital/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://poke.digital/about/</guid>
      <description>Goals Poke has been designed to monitor hundreds of thousands web sites in an efficient and operable manner. Relying on Time Series, and more specificaly Warp10, Poke leverages advanced sliding window algorithms to alert on trends instead on basic checks and thresholds. This metrics approach opens your web monitoring to anomaly detection, outlier, prediction, etc.
Components Poke infrastructure has been designed to reuse a maximum of a Warp 10 infrastructure components like Apache Kafka and Apache HBase, reducing new dependencies like databases.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>